Kansas City Missouri, 64114 816.507.5957 linkedin.com/in/ratalla816 ratalla816.github.io/professional-portfolio rob.atalla@robatalla816.com

Rob Christopher Atalla

CAREER SUMMARY

A driven and tech-savvy professional with nearly a decade of enterprise sales experience, and a certificate in full stack web development from the University of Kansas. In addition to being teachable, personable, and facilitative, has organically sourced hundreds of clients, maintained thousands of vendor relationships, negotiated multi-million-dollar contracts, and continuously managed a profitable P&L.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Node.js, Express.js
- RESTful APIs
- SQL, Sequelize

- MongoDB, MongoDB Atlas, Mongoose
- Webpack, React JS, GraphQL
- Jest, Insomnia, Inquirer
- ORM, MVC, PWA, MERN

SKILLS & ABILITIES

- Graphic design Figma
- Project management
- Context switching
- Presentation delivery

- Contract negotiation
- Solution / enterprise-level sales
- Vendor management
- Pricing analysis

WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

CODE COMMAND | November 2021 FRONT END DEVELOPER / ASSISTANT PROJECT MANAGER GitHub: github.com/ratalla816/code-command Deployment: code-command-team.herokuapp.com

- Collaborate on a team of two front end developers, and two back end developers.
- Develop project theme, title, and content.
- Select, size, and insert images.
- Conduct daily standup meetings with all team members. Reconcile progress with timeline goals, user story and mockup, then communicate results to Project Manager prior to standup.
- Primarily responsible for development of component and container files. Assist team members when needed.

FORGE | September 2021 PROJECT MANAGER / FRONT END DEVELOPER / FLOATER GitHub: github.com/ratalla816/Forge Deployment: forge-team.herokuapp.com

- Manage a team consisting of two front end developers, and two back end developers.
- Prepare and analyze all requirements and necessary documentation.
- Create mockup using Figma.
- Design workflow model and establish timelines.

- Conduct daily standup meetings with all team members. Reconcile progress with timeline goals, user story and mockup prior to standup. Adjust workflow accordingly and communicate strategy and expectations to the team.
- Primarily responsible for development of HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Handlebars. Assist back end developers when needed.

WORK EXPERIENCE

PROBLEM SOLVER I

Amazon | New Century, KS

December 2021 - Present

- Utilizes specialized query methods to process edge case customer returns that cannot be dispositioned using the standard UI workflow.
- Identifies shipments with "null" customer orders then moves product quantities into warehouse inventory.
- Inspects processed return items for quality issues and updates resale conditions if necessary.
- Collaborates with managers and warehouse associates in all departments to manage efficiency, quality, and safety.
- Consistently exceeds completed ticket quotas.

BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT MANAGER

Western Logistics Express | North Kansas City, MO April 2021 - September 2021

- Successfully negotiate contracts with NAPCO Precast for 2,600 shipments over six months with margin yield of \$520,000, and \$3M top-line revenue.
- Create relationships within client organizations through cold calling, network lead prospecting, and email campaigns.
- Analyze market data and trends to develop customer pricing strategies.
- Creatively source and manage vendors.
- Effectively serve as sales coach and accountability partner for new hires.
- Left in September 2021 to finish full stack web development program.

SENIOR ACCOUNT EXECUTIVE

Freightquote / C.H. Robinson | Kansas City, MO May 2014 - April 2021

- Seize single-source opportunities through leveraging proprietary enterprise SaaS solutions. (Enterprise TMS and Freightview).
- Responsible for source and development of multiple division top-ten accounts.
- Demonstrate ability to negotiate resources and priorities with multiple stakeholders in order to drive business results.
- Conduct quarterly business reviews.
- Manage day-to-day customer commitments and maintain service levels through use of metrics and analytics.

EDUCATION

November 2021

CERTIFICATE - FULL STACK WEB APPLICATION DEVELOPMENT

The University of Kansas, Lifelong & Professional Education, Lawrence, Kansas

April 2022

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION

California Coast University, Santa Ana, California